In this world...
Is the destiny of mankind controlled by some transcendental entity or law?
Is it like the hand of God hovering above?
At least it is true...
...that man has no control, even over his own will.
In my eyes, a true friend is someone
who never clings to another's dream.
Someone independent...
...who can find his own reason to live
and follow that path without guidance.
And if anyone tries to crush his
dream, protect it heart and soul.
Even if that person happened to be me.
For me, a true friend...
...is someone whom I consider my equal.
Feel no shame about shape
Weather changes their phrase
Even mother will show you another way
So put your glasses on
Nothing will be wrong
There's no blame. There's no fame
It's up to you
The first words should be found
Whatever holds you back
I...
...can...
I can get it off
Tell me what...
Tell me what you want
I don't know why...
Don't know why...
Don't know why you're afraid
Tell me what...
Tell me what you'd say
I don't know why...
Don't know why...
Too late...
It's too late
The Battle
Griffi...
Sir Griffith!
Princess Charlotte,
what has happened?
Please, take this...
This is a necklace made from lodestone.
It isn't anything extravagant,
but it belonged to the former queen.
It was my mother's keepsake.
Such a precious article of yours...
I cannot accept it.
Please, carry this with you.
There are two of these lodestone,
a male one and a female one.
And each attracts the other.
It's said those who hold companion
stones will always be reunited.
If you would bear this male
stone formed into a necklace...
...it may be attracted
to my female stone necklace.
And thus, you ought to return
safely from the battlefield.
Please, I would like you to have this.
No...
This is a precious keepsake of yours, Princess.
I cannot keep this as my possession.
But...
Therefore, I will return this safely
to you as soon as I return from battle.
Honestly, never before has
the war filled me with such fear.
Sir Griffith, please...
Please stay safe.
Knight, please come forward.
Y-Yes, ma'am...
Please guard Sir Griffith well during this battle.
Certainly, ma'am, on my life.
Let's go.
All right...
Charlotte.
M-Mother.
What do you think you are doing, Charlotte?
What do you mean?
Do not feign ignorance.
You gave that man of lesser stature a present.
It is not your concern who
I choose to give my property to!
That is improper!
You are a member of the royal house.
To think that you gave a present
to someone of such humble origins!
When you talk to that man, concern
yourself with what others might think.
You shall be mindful of your class.
But, Mother...
You have turned sixteen.
You are no longer a child.
Charlotte!
Look how popular we are!
We are taking on the vanguard
position. It's a big responsibility.
Hey, are you nervous?
Nope!
You seem to have lost your nerve.
You're shaking.
Shut up!
I am just excited about the whole thing!
Why is Griffith so late anyway...
March!
For me, a true friend...
...is someone whom I consider my equal.
Oh no, why now?
What's wrong?
You look pale.
It's nothing.
All right, the battle is about to begin!
Charge!
This is not going to be easy!
It's you...
...the Band of the Hawk's
sole female company commander.
So what?
I do not like it...
...a mere woman such as you acting like a knight.
Women are inferior to men in strength,
so what use are they in killing?
If you think so, then come try me.
What's so funny?
I assume that you comfort your
fellow soldiers during the night...
What did you say?
So, due to getting into Griffith's bed,
you must have won your rank...
...as a company commander!
I would like to experience the charm
that you've used on such men.
You bastard!
A battlefield is a sanctuary for men.
What outrageous conduct
would lead a woman here?
I, the leader of the Blue Whale
Super Strong Heavy Assault Knights...
...Lord Adon, will teach
you a lesson for this!
He's coming!
Big sister!
Damn you!
Idiot!
Stay back!
W-What a fighter...
Casca!
Get back, Judeau!
I'll find a way to kill him!
So useless... No wonder
you are all under that woman's thumb.
What was that?
What will you do now?
There is no ground behind you.
Hey, now, look at this.
Well, I see. You look rather pretty
even though you are dressed...
...in the manner of a man.
Now, I will give you a chance.
If you will be an obedient captive,
I will not kill you here.
Being captive means you may serve
as my army's prostitute, of course.
Son of a bitch...
So, you call me a son of a bitch...
Then you will be buried by a bastard you hate!
Big sister!
What?
This is not like you.
Guts...
Commander!
Guts!
Come on.
I don't care who you are. I just want
to swing my sword against someone...
Until I'm so exhausted
that I can't think anymore!
Enough with your stupid remarks!
Well done, I praise you for blocking my strike!
However, a fluke never happens twice!
Can you defend against my special
strike that can even pulverize marble?
This is the spearmanship...
...that has been passed down through
the Coborlwitz family for 140 years.
The ultimate secret technique...
Ganzansenpu...
Ganzansenpu?
What the hell?
A-Amazing...
He beat that monster with only two blows.
Nothing less from our captain.
Way to go!
What's wrong?
It's totally unlike you,
losing your edge in combat.
Get it together or you'll get killed.
H-Hey!
Guts!
Casca!
Never again...
I'll never go in the water with my armor.
Shit.
She's got a serious fever.
It looks bad.
If I make a fire, the enemy
might spot it and find us.
Damn it!
I guess there's no other way.
We did this sort of thing once.
It's no big deal!
What the hell? With that fever of
hers, she thinks she can still fight?
So that's it.
It's pretty tough to be a woman...
Guts and Casca...
The cliff was quite high, but a river
ran below it, so they must have...
You know how Guts is.
They're probably alive, but...
I couldn't see if they
landed safely from that fall.
And the captain was already
injured in the battle...
Casca was not quite herself as well.
We should get a search party
out there right away.
Lord Griffith, you must understand this...
In a battle, our utmost concern
is to conquer the enemy.
It is outrageous to use soldiers who
have been gifted to you by the king...
...to search during a battle
to ensure the safety of a mere...
...troop commander.
Besides, this happened because
they recklessly entered single combat.
No, that's not true...
The Raiders' leader and the famous
female company commander...
The two most skilled commanders
are together, aren't they?
Supposedly, they are able
to take such troubles in stride.
Indeed, I suppose
they will if they are still alive.
Looking back, the morning comes.
Don't find your face in your glass.
Take the moonlight by the tail.
It's a rainy sight. You're shading.
What is that?
It's just the same.
What is trying your crown?
I'm spending my glass, walking back.
So wear my glass. You're fading.
I'm waiting so long.
I'm waiting...